Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katrin and today we have a sad lesson for you.
我是Katrin，今天我们有一节令人悲伤的课程。
This is an intermediate level lesson about what happens when a friend or family member
这是一节中级课程，内容是关于当朋友或家人
dies.
去世时会发生什么。
Exactly.
没错。
So, we have a lot of words that are related to all the preparations for when somebody
所以，我们有很多与为某人去世做准备相关的词汇，
dies and also some phrases that you can say to someone that maybe had a family member
以及一些你可以对可能最近有家人
who recently passed away.
去世的人说的话。
So before we get into all of this, we have a key word that we want to take a look at
在我们开始这一切之前，我们有一个关键词，想先看看
now in Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览部分。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Alright, so in Vocabulary Preview, you have that one word and it's the title of our lesson
好的，在词汇预览中，你看到那个词，也是我们课程的标题，
also, funeral.
葬礼。
Funeral.
So, funeral is an event.
所以，葬礼是一个事件。
It's something that we have.
是我们举办的一种活动。
So basically, a funeral is the time when we mourn someone who has died.
基本上，葬礼是我们哀悼逝者的时刻。
It's a celebration of their life.
是对他们生命的庆祝。
Right.
对。
So it's kind of like a ceremony where you respect that person that passed away, right?
所以有点像一种仪式，你尊重那个去世的人，对吧？
Some people will talk about the person that passed away or maybe, you know, it's time
有些人会谈论逝者，或者，你知道，这是
to maybe honor that person, to as you say, mourn and remember that person.
纪念那个人，如你所说，哀悼并记住那个人。
Right.
对。
So it's very common for people in different religions to have different traditions.
所以不同宗教的人有不同的传统，这很常见。
In some religions, like I think in Christianity, you have a priest who will say some things
在一些宗教中，比如我认为在基督教中，会有牧师说一些
that are very traditional and then say some things about the person who died.
非常传统的话，然后说一些关于逝者的事情。
Other religions have different ceremonies.
其他宗教有不同的仪式。
Right.
对。
So today we're going to take a look at what happens in preparing a funeral.
所以今天我们要看看准备葬礼时会发生什么。
Hi, Daniel.
嗨，Daniel。
How are you holding up?
你还好吗？
I'm greatly sorry for your loss.
我对你的损失深表遗憾。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I'm much better.
我好多了。
I've begun organizing everything for the funeral.
我已经开始安排葬礼的一切事宜。
How's that going?
进展如何？
It's a lot harder than I imagined.
比我想象的要难得多。
There are many things that you have to arrange.
有很多事情需要安排。
I booked a time and date with the funeral home, but I still have a lot of things to
我已经和殡仪馆预约了时间和日期，但我还有很多事情要
do.
做。
Have you brought a burial plot and a casket?
你买了墓地和棺材吗？
No.
没有。
Wendy is being cremated.
Wendy要火化。
She always talked about how she didn't want to be buried.
她总是说她不想被埋葬。
I already chose a cremation urn and we plan to spread the ashes in the ocean.
我已经选好了骨灰盒，我们计划把骨灰撒在海里。
I see.
我明白了。
That sounds like something she would have really liked.
听起来像是她会喜欢的方式。
I'm sure the memorial service will be tasteful.
我相信追悼会会很有品味。
You're doing a great job.
你做得很好。
Thanks.
谢谢。
It hasn't been easy, but luckily we have life insurance and Wendy left behind a detailed
这并不容易，但幸运的是我们有寿险，Wendy留下了一份详细的
will that will sort out any other legal matters.
遗嘱，可以处理其他法律事务。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a pretty interesting dialogue and I'm sure you have a lot of questions regarding some
一段非常有趣的对话，我相信你对听到的一些
of those words and phrases that you heard.
单词和短语有很多疑问。
So why don't we take a look at five key words on Language Takeaway.
那我们来看看语言要点中的五个关键词吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So basically we have two friends in this dialogue who are discussing arrangements for a funeral
基本上，在这段对话中有两个朋友在讨论葬礼的安排，
and one friend is asking the other about his preparations and asks if he's bought a burial
一个朋友问另一个他的准备情况，问他是否买了
plot.
墓地。
Okay, burial plot.
好的，墓地。
Now what is a burial plot and why would you buy one?
什么是墓地，为什么要买一个？
Well, a plot, P-L-O-T, plot is a piece of land.
嗯，plot，P-L-O-T，plot是一块土地。
So you can think about this logically, a burial plot, burial to bury is a place, a space
所以你可以逻辑上理解，burial plot，burial是埋葬，是一个地方，一个
in the ground where we bury a person.
地下的空间，我们埋葬一个人。
Usually you buy one of these at a cemetery, right?
通常你在墓地买一个，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So cemeteries have some, usually a lot of land and you can pay for a piece of land.
所以墓地有一些，通常有很多土地，你可以花钱买一块地。
A small portion.
一小块。
A small portion, yeah.
一小块，是的。
And that's a burial plot.
那就是墓地。
Okay, good.
好的，不错。
And well, our next word is related to what you put into this burial plot, right?
嗯，我们的下一个词与你放进这个墓地的东西有关，对吧？
Somebody dies and what goes into this piece of land is a casket.
有人去世了，放进这块地里的东西是棺材。
That's right.
没错。
And I don't know if any of you are fans of the TV show Six Feet Under, but you'll know
我不知道你们中是否有人是电视剧《六尺之下》的粉丝，但你会从
from this TV show that there are many different kinds of caskets.
这部电视剧中知道有很多不同种类的棺材。
So a casket is a box.
所以棺材是一个盒子。
You can have fancy caskets or you can have wooden caskets that are very simple, like
你可以有华丽的棺材，也可以有非常简单的木制棺材，比如
pine.
松木。
And basically this is the box that the person's body will go into when they're buried.
基本上，这就是人下葬时身体要放进去的盒子。
Right.
对。
Very good.
很好。
So that is called a casket.
所以那叫做棺材。
Well moving on, a new trend I would say in many countries and many people around the
嗯，接着说，我觉得在很多国家有一种新趋势，世界上很多人
world don't want to be buried.
不想被土葬。
So what happens?
那怎么办？
You get cremated.
你会被火化。
Cremated.
火化。
So this is the option for people who are not buried.
所以这是不土葬的人的选择。
In some countries, China for example, I don't think you can be buried.
在一些国家，比如中国，我觉得你不能土葬。
You have to be cremated because there's an issue of space.
你必须火化，因为空间问题。
And this is an option for most people where basically your friend or your loved one, their
对大多数人来说，这是一种选择，基本上你的朋友或亲人，
body is burned and you can collect the remains afterwards.
他们的身体被烧掉，之后你可以收集骨灰。
They're very small.
它们很小。
They're ashes.
它们是骨灰。
So it's like a burning process.
所以这就像燃烧的过程。
Okay, interesting.
好的，有意思。
So the word is to be cremated, to get cremated.
所以这个词是“被火化”，或者“去火化”。
Yeah, his body was cremated.
是的，他的遗体被火化了。
And well as you said, you take the ashes and you can put them in a cremation urn or just
嗯，就像你说的，你拿走骨灰，可以把它们放进火化骨灰瓮或者就是
an urn.
一个骨灰瓮。
Okay, urn.
好的，骨灰瓮。
This might sound like a strange word to you.
这个词对你来说可能听起来有点陌生。
But an urn is a special kind of pot, okay, or a vessel to hold things in.
但骨灰瓮是一种特殊的罐子，或者容器，用来装东西。
So for example, in this case we have a cremation urn that is a special pot, usually very beautiful.
比如，在这种情况下，我们有一个火化骨灰瓮，那是一个特殊的罐子，通常很漂亮。
Sometimes there's a name on it with the deceased person's ashes, his or her remains.
有时上面有名字，装着逝者的骨灰，他或她的遗骸。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
So as you said, it's kind of like a vase or a pot, something very nice and small where
就像你说的，它有点像花瓶或罐子，一个很漂亮的小东西，
you have the person's ashes.
里面装着逝者的骨灰。
All right, so now we know what happened during the funeral.
好了，现在我们知道了葬礼上发生了什么。
We know what happens, how you maybe cremate the person or you put them in a casket.
我们知道了过程，比如你可能火化逝者，或者把他们放进棺材。
And well, what happens afterwards?
嗯，那之后呢？
Well, afterwards you have a memorial service.
嗯，之后会有一个追思会。
Okay, so many people want to know what's the difference between a funeral and a memorial
好的，很多人想知道葬礼和追思会
service.
有什么区别。
In my mind, a funeral is very quiet and sad and you have some respectful words and you
在我看来，葬礼很安静、悲伤，你会说一些敬重的话，
usually put the casket into the ground or have some kind of ceremony.
通常会把棺材放入地下，或者举行某种仪式。
But a memorial service is an opportunity to talk to friends and family, to eat some food,
但追思会是一个机会，可以和亲友交谈，吃些食物，
to have some drinks, to talk about the person who died.
喝点东西，谈论逝者。
It's almost like the party, if that makes sense.
它几乎像一场派对，如果这么说能理解的话。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
It's a get together of people who obviously are trying to give support to their friends
这是一个聚会，人们显然是想给失去逝者的朋友
or their family members who lost that person, but also to talk about that person in a good
或家人提供支持，同时也以积极的方式谈论那个人，
way and all the great memories they had.
以及他们拥有的所有美好回忆。
I guess that's why it's called a memorial service because you remember and you give
我想这就是为什么它叫追思会，因为你回忆并分享
out your memories about that person.
关于那个人的记忆。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, great.
好的，很棒。
So a lot of interesting words there, very specific to this topic, but obviously really
所以这里有很多有趣的词，非常针对这个话题，但显然
important.
非常重要。
So why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue again.
那我们为什么不回去再听一遍对话呢。
Hi Daniel, how are you holding up?
嗨，丹尼尔，你还好吗？
I'm greatly sorry for your loss.
我对你的损失深表遗憾。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I'm doing much better.
我现在好多了。
I've begun organizing everything for the funeral.
我已经开始为葬礼安排一切了。
How's that going?
进展如何？
It's a lot harder than I imagined.
比我想象的要难得多。
There are many things that you have to arrange.
有很多事情需要安排。
I booked a time and date with the funeral home, but I still have a lot of things to
我已经和殡仪馆预约了时间和日期，但我还有很多事情
do.
要做。
Have you brought a burial plot and a casket?
你买了墓地位置和棺材吗？
No, Wendy is being cremated.
没有，温迪要被火化。
She always talked about how she didn't want to be buried.
她总是说她不想被土葬。
I already chose a cremation urn and we plan to spread the ashes in the ocean.
我已经选了一个火化骨灰瓮，我们计划把骨灰撒在海里。
I see.
我明白了。
That sounds like something she would have really liked.
听起来像是她会喜欢的事情。
I'm sure the memorial service will be tasteful.
我相信追思会会办得很得体。
You're doing a great job.
你做得很好。
Thanks.
谢谢。
It hasn't been easy, but luckily we have life insurance and Wendy left behind a detailed
这不容易，但幸运的是我们有寿险，温迪留下了一份详细的
will that will sort out any other legal matters.
遗嘱，会解决其他法律事务。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So we have a couple of phrases, four to be exact, that we want to take a look at now
所以我们现在有几个短语，准确来说是四个，我们想在流利度提升部分
in Fluency Builder.
看一下。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
Okay, this first phrase is a very useful one if you're trying to ask someone about maybe
好的，第一个短语非常有用，如果你想问某人
how they're feeling or someone who's had some problems recently.
他们感觉如何，或者某人最近遇到了一些问题。
You can ask them how things are going.
你可以问他们情况怎么样。
One person says to the other, hi Daniel, how are you holding up?
一个人对另一个人说，嗨，丹尼尔，你还好吗？
Right.
对。
How are you holding up?
你还好吗？
Now you know that to hold up something means to have it in your hands, but in this case
现在你知道“hold up something”意思是把它拿在手里，但在这里
you're talking about how are things going?
你是在问情况怎么样？
Right, but I wouldn't say, hey, how are you holding up?
对，但我不会说，嘿，你还好吗？
Right.
对。
You wouldn't say that to somebody, right?
你不会对别人这么说，对吧？
If normal circumstances.
在正常情况下。
If Marco looks really happy, I won't ask him.
如果马可看起来很开心，我不会问他。
But if someone has passed through a very difficult period, for example, if someone dies in their
但如果有人经历了一段非常艰难的时期，比如，他们家里有人去世了
family or perhaps if they've been very sick or there's some negative or difficult things
或者他们病得很重，或者发生了一些负面或困难的事情
that happened, you can say, how are you holding up?
你可以说，你还好吗？
So basically means how are you dealing with this difficult situation or how are you dealing
所以基本上意思是，你如何应对这个困难的情况，或者你如何应对
with your illness?
你的疾病？
How are you holding up?
你还好吗？
Or how are you holding up with your in-laws?
或者你和你的姻亲相处得怎么样？
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
How are you dealing with that difficult situation?
你如何应对那个困难的情况？
And then the person complimented this by saying, and this is a very good phrase, this whole
然后那个人补充说，这是一个非常好的短语，整个
sentence is very useful if you want to say something nice to a person that has recently
句子非常有用，如果你想对最近失去亲人的人说些好话。
lost someone.
失去亲人的人。
You say, I am greatly sorry for your loss.
你说，我对你的损失深表遗憾。
Okay, so you might have heard the word loss before, lose, loss.
好的，你可能以前听过“loss”这个词，失去，损失。
Loss is a noun, it's a thing.
“Loss”是一个名词，是一个事物。
We normally say this about people who have died because you don't want to say, I'm really
我们通常用这个词来形容去世的人，因为你不想说，我真的很
sorry for your dead brother.
为你死去的兄弟感到难过。
It's sad, it's very rude, too direct.
这很悲伤，很粗鲁，太直接了。
So in English we say, I'm greatly sorry for your loss, for this part of your life that
所以在英语中我们说，我对你的损失深表遗憾，对你生命中已经逝去的
has gone away.
这部分。
You can also say, I'm very sorry for your loss.
你也可以说，我对你的损失非常抱歉。
This is a standard phrase for funerals and memorial services.
这是葬礼和追悼会上的标准用语。
So if somebody's brother died, you go up to that person and you can say, I am greatly
所以如果某人的兄弟去世了，你走到那个人面前可以说，我对你的损失
sorry for your loss.
深表遗憾。
I am very sorry for your loss.
我对你的损失非常抱歉。
That's what you say.
这就是你要说的。
And it's very respectful and it's very nice to say.
这样说非常尊重，也非常好。
Yes, it's very nice.
是的，非常好。
All right, so now moving on, we've said that the person is sorry and everything, but then
好的，现在我们继续，我们已经说了那个人很抱歉等等，但接着
they were talking about the girl Wendy and that she had life insurance and that she also
他们谈到了那个叫温蒂的女孩，她有人寿保险，还留下了
left behind a detailed will.
一份详细的遗嘱。
Does that mean she forgot it?
这是不是意味着她忘了？
She forgot it, but that can mean that, right?
她忘了，但也可以有那个意思，对吧？
Right.
对。
This is a phrase that has a couple different meanings.
这个短语有几个不同的意思。
And so it's important to look at this one when we're talking about someone who has died,
所以当我们谈论一个去世的人，他留下了什么东西时，看这个短语很重要。
who left behind something.
留下了什么东西。
It means that they have completed it in this case or it survives them.
在这种情况下，意思是他们已经完成了，或者它比他们活得更久。
So they left that for you.
所以他们为你留下了那个。
Because as you said, it has a couple of different meanings like to leave behind can be to lose
因为正如你所说，它有几个不同的意思，比如“leave behind”可以表示丢失
or to forget.
或忘记。
But in this case, specifically, it's to leave for you.
但在这个具体情况下，它是为你留下的。
Yeah.
是的。
For example, you could say he died and he left behind three children.
例如，你可以说他去世了，留下了三个孩子。
That means that he had three children when he died and they're still alive.
意思是他在去世时有三个孩子，他们还活着。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
Very interesting phrase, to leave something behind.
非常有趣的短语，“留下某物”。
And so she left behind a detailed will and that's going to sort out any other legal matters.
所以她留下了一份详细的遗嘱，这将解决任何其他法律问题。
To sort out.
解决。
This is a great verb.
这是一个很棒的动词。
This is a verbal phrase that we hear a lot with documents and wills and things like this.
这是一个动词短语，我们在文件和遗嘱之类的东西中经常听到。
Basically, to sort out means to solve problems or to fix or to amend.
基本上，“sort out”意思是解决问题或修复或修正。
For example, have you sorted out that problem you had with your plane tickets?
例如，你解决你机票的问题了吗？
Okay.
好的。
To sort out.
解决。
So have you fixed those problems or have you solved those problems that you had with your
所以，你解决你机票的那些问题了吗？
plane tickets?
或者你解决你机票的那些问题了吗？
To sort out, to fix, to make arrangements for.
解决，修复，做出安排。
Very, very useful phrase.
非常非常有用的短语。
Very useful phrase.
非常有用的短语。
Okay.
好的。
So four key phrases there, really good ones.
所以这里有四个关键短语，真的很好。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
我们为什么不回去，听一下对话，然后我们会回来再聊一会儿。
Hi Daniel.
嗨，丹尼尔。
How are you holding up?
你还好吗？
I'm greatly sorry for your loss.
我对你的损失深表遗憾。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I'm doing much better.
我好多了。
I've begun organizing everything for the funeral.
我已经开始安排葬礼的一切事宜了。
How's that going?
进展如何？
It's a lot harder than I imagined.
比我想象的要难得多。
There are many things that you have to arrange.
有很多事情需要安排。
I booked a time and date with the funeral home, but I still have a lot of things to
我已经和殡仪馆预约了时间和日期，但还有很多事情要
do.
做。
Have you brought a burial plot and a casket?
你买好墓地跟棺材了吗？
No.
没有。
Wendy is being cremated.
温迪要火化。
She always talked about how she didn't want to be buried.
她一直说她不想被土葬。
I already chose a cremation urn and we plan to spread the ashes in the ocean.
我已经选好了骨灰盒，我们打算把骨灰撒到海里。
I see.
我明白了。
That sounds like something she would have really liked.
听起来她应该会很喜欢这样。
I'm sure the memorial service will be tasteful.
我相信追悼会一定会办得很得体。
You're doing a great job.
你做得很好。
Thanks.
谢谢。
It hasn't been easy, but luckily we have life insurance and Wendy left behind a detailed
这不容易，但幸好我们有寿险，而且温迪留下了一份详细的
will that will sort out any other legal matters.
遗嘱，能处理其他法律事务。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now, talking about funerals, there's an interesting word.
那么，说到葬礼，有个有趣的词。
What is it called when a person speaks at a funeral?
在葬礼上发言叫什么？
Well, normally at a funeral, a loved one or friend will give a eulogy.
嗯，通常在葬礼上，亲友会致悼词。
Eulogy.
悼词。
Okay, that's E-U, right?
好的，是E-U开头，对吧？
E-U.
E-U。
It looks like a funny word, but it's very important and it's something that you hear
这个词看起来有点奇怪，但它很重要，而且你经常能听到
a lot.
它。
Who will give the eulogy?
谁会致悼词？
Or his son will give the eulogy.
或者他儿子会致悼词。
So this is maybe the keynote address in a funeral.
所以这可能是葬礼上的主题演讲。
This is the important speech where someone will discuss the person who has died and his
这是一段重要的讲话，有人会谈论逝者及其
or her contributions and life.
贡献和生平。
Right.
对。
Okay, so that's called a eulogy.
好的，那就叫悼词。
It's really interesting because it's kind of a word that you don't really use much and
这很有意思，因为这个词不太常用，
you wouldn't really know it.
你可能不太了解。
For example, I didn't really know about it until I saw it in a movie when he made a mistake.
比如，我以前也不太知道，直到我在一部电影里看到有人搞错了。
He said googology or something like that.
他说成了“googology”之类的。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Yeah, it was in a comedy.
是啊，那是一部喜剧片。
But very interesting words.
但这个词很有意思。
It's a sad topic, but it happens sometimes.
这是个悲伤的话题，但有时难免会遇到。
You have to deal with these things and so if you have to do it in English, well, what
你必须处理这些事情，所以如果你需要用英语来做，那么
better way than to learn all of these things which could come in handy sometimes.
学习这些可能派上用场的词汇再好不过了。
That's right.
没错。
And you never know, you're watching a movie or something and this comes up.
而且说不定哪天你看电影什么的就会碰到。
There are a lot of comedies, like you said, we call them black comedies.
有很多喜剧片，就像你说的，我们称之为黑色喜剧。
It means they're very dark and strange.
意思是它们很黑暗、很怪异。
And they, like Four Weddings and a Funeral is a very famous English movie about this
比如《四个婚礼和一个葬礼》就是一部非常著名的关于这类
kind of thing.
事情的英国电影。
And so this is useful vocabulary and some useful phrases for those situations as well.
所以这些词汇和短语在这些场合也很有用。
Exactly.
正是。
And I remember I met somebody who, I remember I knew somebody who met a casket salesman.
我记得我认识一个人，他遇到过卖棺材的推销员。
Really?
真的吗？
Sold caskets.
卖棺材的。
That's an interesting job.
那工作挺有意思的。
Yeah, so you never know.
是啊，所以说不定哪天就会用到。
You never know.
说不定哪天就会用到。
Well, I hope you've enjoyed this lesson.
好了，希望你喜欢这节课。
Not too dark for you, but please do remember to ask us any questions or practice some of
希望不会让你觉得太沉重，但请记得在我们的网站EnglishPod.com上提问或练习
your new words and phrases on our website, EnglishPod.com.
一些新词和短语。
All right, we'll see you guys there.
好的，我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。
Have a good week.
祝一周愉快。